A Guide to the Sam Bowman Papers, 1845-1967
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Sam Bowman Papers, 1845-1967
Special Collections, James Madison University
3092
This collection consists of one Hollinger box containing one folder and seven ledgers.
This collection consists of miscellaneous materials and seven business ledgers of the Bowman family dairy farm in Rockingham County, Va.
Bowman family
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Library by Sam Bowman, April 1999.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of one Hollinger box containing one folder of miscellaneous materials and seven business ledgers that document operations of the Bowman family dairy farm in Rockingham County, VA, 1845- 1967, with the bulk of material covering 1941-1967.
Contents List
- Miscellaneous Materials: 1859-1960, Includes 1859 and 1865 tax receipts; 1862 receipt for military supplies of 20 bushels of corn; 1882 Constitution of the West Rockingham Mutual Fire Insurance Company; 1891 receipt for printing claim for property taken by U.S. soldiers in Civil War; 1929 timber contract; 1942 Certificates of War Necessity for vehicle; summary of the S.R. Bowman Estate, 1936-1960. (Box-folder 1)
- Ledgers: 1848-1967 (Box 1)
  - Ledger 1: 1848-1857
  - Ledger 2: 1941-1947
  - Ledger 3: 1947-1952
  - Ledger 4: 1953-1957
  - Ledger 5: 1958-1959
  - Ledger 6: 1960-1967
- Ledger 7: 1963-1967 (Box 1)
  - Partnership book of R.L. and S.R. Bowman